and now the most difficult
а теперь самая сложная задача
olympiad task I had it was at school in the
олимпиадная у меня было это в школе в
eighth grade at the olympiad like this
восьмом классе на Олимпиаде такая
how much is 100% of 100
сколько будет 100% от 100
Calculate 100% of 100 Yes Calculate using the
Посчитай 100% от 100 Да Посчитай по
formula Well that will be a different formula
формуле Ну это уже другая формула будет
yes yes another one if only I could
да да другая
remember it correctly 100% of
правильно вспомнить бы её ещё 100% от
Hello, hello, don't switch, I'm not arguing, I'm
привет Не Переключайся я не ссорюсь я
originally from Russia, I live in America in
сам из России родом живу в Америке в
California for 18 years, I've seen fires
Калифорнии 18 лет видела у нас пожары
going on here, Yes, I was stunned. By the way, how is it going,
идут Да я офигела Кстати как там вообще
my dacha burned down
у меня дача сгорела
completely, stunned. And how will the state
полностью А как это государство
compensate for the damage or is there insurance?
будет возмещать ущерб или страховка У
We have  we insure Yes we have insurance
нас Мы страхуем Да у нас есть страховки
We have fires once every 5 years Yes there are some
у нас раз в 5 лет пожары есть да такие
but it's just so simple that nothing
но прям такой просто даже ничего не
can put it out You saw how
может тушить такой ветер Ты видела как
McDonald's burned it spread all over the
там Макдональдс с горел это по всему
world Yes And where are you from Horrible
миру разошлось да А ты сама откуда Ужас
I'm from Kaliningrad
Я с Калининграда
Konigsberg Yes  my dad is in  Kaliningrad
кёнигсберг Да у меня батя в Калининграде
was born Wow So you see the world as a
родился Нифига себе Так что видишь мир
round You are 18 years old yes Who are you
круглый Тебе 18 лет есть да На кого
studying to be a
учишься на
philologist What
филолога Какая
philology just general philology Well
филология просто филология общая Ну а
what exactly
что что именно
Well I understand what you are asking about But I do
Ну я понимаю про что ты спрашиваешь Но я
n't even know we don't have a department
даже не знаю у нас нету подразделения
like just philology and that's it  Well, what are you
типа просто филология и всё Ну что вы
studying? What
изучаете Какие
subjects? Well, I just started studying. I'm
предметы Ну я только начала учиться У
only in my first year and it turns out that we've
меня только первый курс и мы получается
completed the first semester. Well, we started studying Old
за первый семестр прошли Ну стали учить
Church Slavonic, modern Russian,
старославянский современный русский
phonetics, introduction to linguistics,
фонетика введение в языкознания
English, everything. And also org. Well, it's like in
английский всё А ещё орг Ну это Как в
school, there's a conversation about something
школе типа там разговор о
important. I just  philologist by education
важном Я просто филолог по образованию
also came in handy in life Well,
тоже ничего себе пригодилось в жизни Ну
I have a specific one, I have
у меня специфически у меня
Romano-Germanic philology Well, yes, I
романо-германская филология Ну вот да Я
think you asked about this, but
вот думаю ты про это и спрашивал но у
I don’t have that type I don’t have that type I studied
меня нету такого типа я нет так Я изучал
I studied at the University of Sacramento in California,
Я в университете Сакраменто в Калифорнии
as it were  Holy [ __ ] But it
как бы учился Нифига себе А вот
turns out that it’s interesting to you as a
получается вот интересно тебе как
philologist
филологу
in our Russian language it’s written as milk and
в нашем русском языке пишется молоко а
read as
читается
moloko we went through this in the first
молоко мы это проходили в первом
semester
семестре потому
because damn Good question now I need to
что блин Хороший вопрос сейчас надо
remember well there’s something like  related to In short, when you do a transcription, there appears, Lord, well, there is a weak position for the letters, right Yes, but why Look, this is why in the Ukrainian language they write milk and read milk, that's how they write in the Ukrainian language, this is how they read And in Russian we write like this and read we write incorrectly How Ukrainians milk but they read Correctly we read incorrectly Why did it happen not It seems to me we do not read correctly or incorrectly simply there was a single language Slavic Old Church Slavonic and from it other languages ​​have already emerged Belarusian Ukrainian Russian and depending on the territory already people themselves they started to adjust for themselves how to read and describe why they didn't adjust because different peoples different countries look The thing is that languages ​​writing When did it appear Yes at a certain point in time Yeah Yes here's grammar And so on Yes the thing is that spelling is obtained when a letter arrived on Rus Cyrillic Cyrillic Yes, here they wrote down the words We received a letter from Kyiv in Russia, first it came from Kyiv, in Kyiv Prince Vladimir baptized Rus there the Greeks brought it
вспомнить ну там что-то типа связанно с
Cyrillic so that's where all the writing was in Russia While there were no cities there then the princes founded it And so on and they brought it here in writing now it turns out uh Greek these uh monks who taught writing they gave the Cyrillic alphabet and wrote it down like this is how it was read that's how it was written, that's how milk is written, in fact, and in the Russian language, yes, a letter came from Kyiv where milk was written, but our dialect was not like that, yeah, in our regions, you know, there's Vologda, there's acat, and this is fir, aka, yeah at akali because we had a non-Slavic population Athena was Hungarian So they brought us Slavic writing from Kyiv Yes they wrote milk And we read anyway with our Akane yeah that's all a joke It's interesting that is it turns out Ukrainian language Yes it is more correct It is heir of this Old Church Slavonic Yes, we have a language Yes, it is already A little spoiled by the way We also write yes, we write it Yes, and we read it Yes, we have it its other More  they say Yes, for example, yes,
ины Ещё говорят Да например да вот
Ukrainians write yes, Ukrainians write that
украинцы пишут да украинцы пишут того
milk and read that milk But we read
молоко и читают того молоко А мы читаем
that milk not at all like that True, well,
того молоко вообще не так Правда
well, well, they explained this to us at the
вот ну да ну нам это объясняли на
introduction to linguistics, but I
введение в языкознании как раз но я
honestly don’t remember how the teacher explained it there,
честно уже не помню как там объяснял
he almost  I explained it differently than
преподаватель он чуть иначе объяснял чем
you did, but it's still an interesting idea, but
вы но всё равно тоже интересная мысль но
I don't know. It doesn't matter to me. Who
я не знаю мне как-то Неважно кто как
speaks what language there is, what
разговаривает на каком там языке какой
dialect there is, it's just important, like, if
там говор просто главное типа если
it's clear, then Okay, that's cool. I don't know. I
понятно то Окей круто вот не знаю
got it. And what do you think? Why are
понял А как считаешь Почему сейчас воюет
Russia and
Россия и
Ukraine at war now?  Why is Russia at war with Ukraine?
Украина Почему Россия с Украиной воюет
Yes Oh, such questions, but I have
Да Ой такие вопросы но у меня есть по
an opinion on this matter. I don't know how
этому поводу мнение Я не знаю насколько
correct it is, but it's mine. I believe that
оно правильно но оно моё Я считаю что
it is not Russia that is at war with Ukraine, but Russia that
тут не Россия воюет с Украиной а Россия
is at war with NATO countries on the territory of
воюет со странами НАТО на территории
Ukraine, as it once was.  with Korea
Украины как это было когда-то с Кореей
when the Soviet Union On the territory of
когда Советский Союз На территории
North Korea the current one fought with the USA
Северной Кореи нынешний воевал с США
which was on the territory of South Korea
которая была на территории Южной Кореи
yes Well then look then not the Soviet
да Ну тогда смотри тогда не Советский
Union and the USA fought on the territory of another
Союз и США воевали на территории другого
state Korea now War The war
государства Кореи сейчас Война Война
is going on on the territory of
идёт на территории
Russia well there Yes also captured  yes
России ну там Да тоже захватывается да
Kursk Kursk region is still
Курска Курская область до сих пор
captured Yes, the territory of the
захвачена Да обстреливает территория
Russian Federation is being shelled, that is, it is a war
Российской Федерации то есть э война
because troops are already starting
потому что уже войска начинают
to break through into the country and there
пробиваться в страну и уже и на нашей
is already a war on our territory but I am just saying that
территории есть война но я просто говорю
initially it started in Ukraine
изначально началась же она на Украине
I don’t know I think that Russia  in general, it is
вот не знаю я считаю что Россия в общем
not fighting with Ukraine, but with the US and
не с Украиной воюет А с США и странами
NATO countries. Well, it is also unclear if
НАТО Ну как бы тут тоже непонятно если
Russia is fighting with the US and NATO countries.
Россия воюет с США и странами НАТО
Why are NATO countries shelling Russia, but
Почему страны НАТО обстреливают Россию а
Russia is not shelling
Россия не обстреливает страны
NATO countries. Probably because I don’t know what
НАТО Наверное потому что не знаю в что
makes no sense. I honestly don’t know.  I mean, there is no
нет смысла Я честно не знаю В смысле нет
point, there is no point in shelling
смысла нет смысла обстреливать страны
NATO countries, it is shelling the Russian
НАТО на обстреливает Российскую
Federation. My mother in Rostov
Федерацию У меня мама в Ростове типа
is worried about drones flying in, yes. And in the
прилёты беспилотников переживает да А в
US,
США спокойно
everything is calm, well, by the time you get to the US,
всё ну до США пока доберёшься
you will get lost. So, what about Alaska? It
так потеряешься Так в чём по Аляске
is possible, 4 km from Russia. Why? Who needs it?
Можно же 4 км от Росси мо Зачем Кому это
need Well, if if Russia is fighting with
надо Ну так если если Россия воюет с
NATO somehow it turns out Russia is fighting with
НАТО как-то получается Россия воюет с
NATO Russia is not fighting with NATO the US but at the
Нато у России поте не с НАТО США но при
same time NATO is also taking part in the
этом НАТО тоже принимает участие в ф
supply Ho look Russia is fighting with the US Yes the
поставки Хо смотри Россия воюет с США Да
US is not  lost not a single soldier Russia
США не потеряла ни одного солдата Россия
lost 800,000
потеряла 800.000
people I have no idea at all but how is it that
людей вообще без понятия всё но как это
Russia is fighting with the US but the US has absolutely no losses
Россия воюет с США но у США нету потерь
And Russia has such losses maybe I do
абсолютно А у России такие потери может
n’t know maybe the US is just a
не знаю может к США как раз-таки
supply Well, like a supply from NATO
поставка Ну как поставка типа из НАТО
just-  weapons people soldiers Well and the
как раз-таки оружие люди Солдаты Ну и
USA They are not using their own soldiers
США Они же не своих солдатов используют
but the soldier who is on the territory of Ukraine
а солдат который на территории Украины
that is yes this is
находится то есть да это
half in the USA - these are like hands and
полу во США - это как бы вот руки а
Ukrainians are little people who are on a
украинцы - это человечки которые вот на
string Yes right Well look
ниточка Да правильно Ну смотри воюет
Ukraine is fighting oh USA  and Russia yes yes yes yes
Украина ой США и Россия да да да да
look Russia is fighting with the USA The USA does not lose
смотри Россия воюет с США США не теряет
a single soldier Russia loses 800,000
ни одного солдата Россия теряет 800.000
in 3 years how does this
за 3 года как так
happen I don’t know Ask the
получается Не знаю Спросите
government Well I just don’t understand
правительство Ну просто я не понимаю в
what the point of such a war with the USA is If the
чём тогда суть такой войны с США Если
USA is some kind of sound a  eh then what is the essence of
США звук какой-то а э в чём тогда суть
such a war with the USA If for the USA it is not a
такой войны с США Если для США Это не
problem but for Russia it is a problem Well that's what I'm
проблема а для России проблема Ну вот я
saying the USA Why doesn't it lose because
и говорю США Почему не теряет потому что
they don't use their own soldiers but foreign ones
они не своих солдат используют а чужих
and Russia Why did it get involved in this so
так а Россия Зачем в это ввязалась так
that  to fight with the USA
чтобы воевать с США
when the USA you are foreign soldiers and ROSI is
когда США вы чужими солдатами а РОСИ
aggressive
агрессировать
slightly hinted that there will soon be aggression
чуть намекнула что будет скоро агрессия
against you get ready as the USA hinted
на вас готовьтесь как США намекнула
And by suggesting that Ukraine join
А тем что предложила Украине вступить в
NATO it is dangerous for Russia because
НАТО это опасно для России потому что
why like there Belarus Kazakhstan they are
почему типа там Беларусия Казахстан они
calm they do not join because well
спокойны они не вступают потому что ну
they understand what will happen and Ukraine is Well, a
понимают что будет а Украина она Ну
little bit lost, that is, they
чуть-чуть потеряна то есть её ни туда ни
don’t accept it here or there because there was
сюда не принимают потому что была
aggression in the 2000s, there in the
агрессия в нулевые там в четырнадцатые
1914s. That’s all that happened there,
годы Вот это всё короче происходило там
well, you understand what happened. Well, the US
ну Сами понимаете что было Вот и ну США
sees that Ukraine and  so Russia doesn't
видит что вот Украина и так Россию не
like you love Kazakhstan loves Russia
любит ю любит Казахстан Россию любит
China loves Russia you put all this in your ears
Китай Россию любит те это в уши всё
Who gave you all this Where did you
вложил Кто тебе это всё вло Откуда ты
read this history that history
это прочитала история что история
history just read history and came to
историю просто читала историю и сделала
this conclusion I don't read the news I don't
такой вывод Я не читаю новости Я не
watch TV and I generally don't  I
смотрю телевизор и я вообще о политике
don't talk about politics, that is, well, I
не разговариваю то есть ну вот у меня
have formed my opinion. I am guided by it.
сложилось моё мнение Я им и двигаюсь Всё
If there is some new interesting
если есть какое-то новое интересное
opinion, of course I will listen.
мнение Я конечно выслушаю Кто
Who is the head of the Government of the Russian Federation? Lord, I have no idea. Mishustin. And who is the head of the State Duma of the
А кто глава государственной Думы
Russian Federation?  no idea Volodin
Российской Федерации без понятия Володин
That is, you don't know some
То есть ты не знаешь какие-то
basic things about your country But
элементарные вещи со своей страны Но ты
here you start to analyze NATO It's cool Well,
тут начинаешь НАТО разбира прикольно ну
you asked me yourself I answered You
вы сами меня спросили я ответила
asked my opinion I told him everything
спросили моё мнение Я его сказала всё в
that is simple for me Yes, it's not clear How do you
чём мне просто Да непонятно Откуда ты
know everything about America  if you don't
так всё знаешь про Америку если не
know about
знаешь про
Russia Yes, I'm not interested in either America or Russia
Россию Да я вообще ни Америка ни Россия
I don't care I live
не интересуюсь мне всё равно Я живу
my life I just know my laws
своей жизнью Я знаю просто свои законы
my rights and responsibilities all this is all
свои права и обязанности всё это всё что
I know some surnames names I be
я знаю каких-то там фамилий имён я бе у
you have rights in
тебя права есть в
Russia  Yes, damn, the most basic ones that the
России Да блин самый базовые которые по
whole world
все мирно вот этой декларации о правах
doesn't know about this declaration of human rights No, no, no, in Russia,
человека не зна Нет нет нет в в России
in Russia, let's
еди в России Давайте России в России
cancel the declaration of human rights in Russia,
декларацию о правах человека отменили
okay Well, according to the Constitution of the Russian
хорошо Ну по Конституции Российской
Federation, a person has the right to life, the
Федерации у человека есть право на жизнь
right to vote  well, what rights can I
э право голоса на э ну какие права вам
tell you at all?
сказать вообще
Name
я Назови
them: for life, for freedom of speech, for the right
их на жизнь на свободу слова на право
to vote, for the right to be elected to
голосования на Право быть избранным в
government bodies, for
правительственные органы
almost everything there is a right. I don’t know.
на почти на всё есть право Я не знаю То
That is, look at all the rights that you named,
есть смотри все которые ты назвал эти
these rights in Russia. No, come on.  Let's
права этих прав в России Нет давай
start with the right to Freedoms  words if
начнём с права на Свободы слова если у
you don't have this I agree with this I
вас нет с этим я согласна с этим я
agree not to prove this I
согласна не доказывать с этим я
agree with this the Constitution
согласна Конституции
is written from the word but in fact this
написано с слова но по факту этой
Freedom of speech No I agree with you with this
Свободы слова Нет с этим я с вами
I even proved this to my friend in the summer
согласна я это даже своему другу летом
so look why are you
доказывала так то смотри то зачем ж ты
I have a legal
мне навались Я человек с юридическим
education Yes I do No you told me to
образованием Да я так Нет вы мне сказали
just say my rights according to the Constitution
просто сказать свои права по Конституции
everything that is written in the Constitution if I
всё что написано в Конституции сза ели
told you my opinion about rights then
вам сказать моё мнение по поводу прав то
I don't agree with half of it said what
я с половиной не согласна сказал какие у
rights you have not what is written  your
тебя есть права не то что написано у вас
constitution is a piece of paper that you can
конститу это бумажка которой можно
rub off it doesn't work for you I mean
потереться она у вас не действует я вот
what rights do you really have in Russia
какие у тебя права реально есть в России
really Yeah damn I don't know there are many rights there are
реально Да блин не знаю много прав есть
rights as long as I don't infringe on the rights of another
права пока я не задену права другого
person what rights name what rights there
человека какие назви какие права наме
are no rights to freedom of speech Freedom  there are words but then it is
нету Свобода слова есть но она потом
punished not that means it is not there So what
карается не вот значит её нету Так какое
right do you have then Well to life to
у тебя право есть тогда Ну на жизнь на
protect
защиту
life too
жизни тоже
there is no but I am living now Yeah
нету ну я сечас живу
well Kadyrovites can you In short nothing will
Да ну кадыровцы могут тебя Короче ничего
happen to them for this but let's even for the sake of
им за это не будет а давайте даже ради
interest according to the Constitution  let's go I'll
интереса по Конституции пройдёмся я
get her now So why the Constitution
сейчас её доста Так зачем Конституция
look at your Constitution it's not valid
смотри у вас Конституция не действует
it's all just a piece of paper I'm saying
всё она бумажка просто да я говорю
because I don't remember word for word damn
потому что я не помню слово в слово блин
all the rights I studied them in the ninth grade
всех прав Я их учила в девятом классе
before the exam Now I don't remember them at all
перед экзаменом Сейчас я их вообще не
I don't care Which  I have
помню меня не волнуют Какие у меня есть
rights as long as I haven't broken the law, that means I
права пока я закон не нарушила значит я
live the way I want, wait
живу как хочу
a second, I got the Constitution from
секундочку я же достала Конституция от
Lenin to
Ленина до
Putin, we can start with Lenin, if so, let's
Путина можем начать с Ленина если давай
start with Lenin. What do you have
начни с Ленина Что там у вас
written there, really, start with Lenin,
написано реально с Ленина
there are workers' rights,
начать тут есть права трудящиеся
some kind of people's rights  in short
какие-то права народа короче
Neva article in the Russian Federation
Нева статья в Российской Федерации
recognizes the
призна
freedom of man the basic rights and freedoms of
свобо человека основные права и свободы
man they alienate everyone from
человека они отчуждать каждому от
birth All are equal before the law and the court I
рождения Все равны перед законом и судом
don’t know what else is here Everyone has the
не знаю что тут ещё есть Каждый имеет
right to life Everyone has the right to
право на жизнь Каждый имеет право на
free and liberty and personal
свободную и свободу и личную
inviolability Everyone has the right to
неприкосновенность Каждый имеет право на
privacy of private life is all
неприкосновенность частной жизни это всё
carried out I think What
осуществляется Я считаю Какое
is carried out Hello What is carried out
осуществляется Алло Какое осуществляется
if the home is inviolable while the
если жилище неприкосновенно пока жи
home is also in yours
жилище тоже у вас
so here in the article py just the same
так здесь в статье пй как раз таки
the condition is written the home is inviolable  no
написано условие жилище неприкосновенно
one has the right to enter a home
никто не в праве проникать в жилище
against the will of the persons living there,
против воли проживающих в нём лиц Иначе
except in cases established by the Federal
как в случаях установленных Федеральным
Law or on the basis of a court
Законом или на основании судебного
decision, that is, you have already decided, in
решения то есть у вас У вас уже решили
short, you can, like, enter the
да что короче можно типа входить в
home, everything is already gone, okay, okay, in short,
жилище всё уже нету Да окей Окей короче
look, I  I'll tell you You can
смотри я тебе скажу Ты можешь эту книжку
just throw this book away It doesn't mean
просто выкинуть она ничего не значит у
anything to you It doesn't mean anything You don't have justice
вас она ничего у вас нет правосудия у
You don't have justice
вас нет правосудия
What can I say Throw it away
что скаже выкинь
at all No, I don't want to save it There
вообще Да не я хочу её сохранить
should be some kind of a stand for the mug
поставка же для кружки должна быть
Here is a stand Constitution of
какая-то Вот подставка Конституция
Russia stand for a mug  this is really
России подставка для кружки это реально
ka Listen, who do you think is
ка Слушай а как ты считаешь кто виноват
specifically to blame for this war between Russia and Ukraine,
конкретно в этой войне России и Украины
more precisely Russia and the
точнее Росси
USA Well, specifically, who is
США Ну конкретно Кто в США
to blame in the USA Biden is some kind of
виноват байден дед старый какой-то
strange old man, an old man - it's Putin Well,
странный дед старый - это Путин Ну
Biden is even older And how is Biden to blame
байден ещё старее А чем байден виноват
Well, some kind of senile man  I don't
Ну маразматик какой-то не
know listen okay that's interesting Okay
знаю слушай хорошо вот интересно Ладно
Biden is a senile man everything is the USA And why is it that
байден маразматик всё США А почему вот
Russia has oil gas gold diamonds the
Россия имеет нефть газ золото алмазы
richest country and people live poorer
богатейшая держава а люди живут беднее
than in
чем в
Europe because  that all the money goes to
Европе потому что все деньги идут на
weapons I don't know for defense I honestly don't
оружие не знаю на защиту Я честно я не
know where the money goes I ask myself
знаю куда уходят деньги я сама задаюсь
this question why do we have a lot of
этим вопросом почему у нас дофига
resources and people live like this how they
ресурсов а люди живут вот так вот как и
live Well let's try The thing is that
живут Ну давай попробуем Дело в том что
I like to lead people to smart  I
я люблю людей подводить к умным мыслям
provoke thoughts into thinking
провоцирую их на мыслительную
activity How is it that you
деятельность Да как так получается вы
sold gas to all of Europe all of Europe
продавали газ всей Европе вся Европа
paid for gas sold oil to the whole
платила за газ продавали нефть всему
world diamonds one of the top powers in
миру алмазы одна топовых держав по
Diamonds Maybe the dollar influences this
Алмаза А может быть на это влияет доллар
How does the dollar influence it - it's a world currency
Как влияет доллар - это ж мировая валюта
And what Well look if  and all Europeans
И что Ну смотри если и у всех европейцев
Well the dollar is the euro and we have the ruble which is
Ну доллар евро а у нас рубль который
always falling Well that's right Well yes
вечно падает что Ну правильно Ну да Ну
Well look you sell these dollars to
вот смотри ты вы за эти доллары продаёте
poor Europeans who buy gas from you and
бедные европейцы покупают у вас газ
give you their money Yes
отдают вам свои деньги Да
And you collect money for all this gas and
А вы собираете деньги за весь этот газ и
live in poverty  what's
живёте бедно в чём
the joke maybe taxes are connected with this
прикол может налоги с этим связаны
taxes in Europe are higher than in Russia Well that's
налоги в Европе выше чем в России Ну вот
why and well taxes what do they go to the
и поэтому и ну налоги они на что идут на
state to improve people's lives And
государство на улучшение жизни людей А
when taxes are higher naturally more
когда налоги больше естественно больше
money goes to  Improving the quality of life in
денег идёт на Улучшение качества жизни в
Russia, taxes are lower than in Europe and
России же налоги ниже чем в Европе и
because of this, less money goes to the
из-за этого меньше денег идёт в
state I don't know Well, you are
государстве Я не знаю Ну вы вы
asking my opinion, what are you
спрашиваете моё мнение что вы меня
judging me for, this is mine, I was silent, I was silent But
осуждаете это мо я молчал я молчал А вот
this is what happened, I heard everything,
это что было я всё слышала
I tried  keep quiet Yes listen
Я старался промолчать Да слуша Сколько
How much is 11% of
сколько будет 11% от
oh well I need to calculate
а ну мне надо посчитать
a second
секунду
11 100
11 100
Well
Ну
11 100 is
11 100 это
oh 1 for
ой 1 за
1 1.1 no right right And how much
1 1,1 нет правильно правильно А сколько
is 20% of
будет 20% от
100 now I have you know here eh
100 сейчас у меня знаете вот э вот
here is this mathematical thing  like 100
математическая вот эта штучка типа 100 -
is 100 20 is x 20 at 100 is 2 is
это 100 20 - это x 20 у 100 это 2 это
2000 2000 100
2000 2000 100
is 20 oh no that's not a lot not that's a
получается 20 ой нет не это много не это
lot less will be yes less something a
много меньше будет да меньше что-то
lot Well 11% was
много Ну 11% это ж было
1.1 then 20%
1,1 то 20% -
is  five Let's say two so I said two but
это пять Пусть два так я сказала два а
no I 20 said two two is right
нет я 20 сказала два два правильно
Okay and now the most difficult task
Хорошо а теперь самая сложная задача
I had an Olympiad, it was at school in the
олимпиадная у меня было это в школе в
eighth grade at the Olympiad,
восьмом классе на Олимпиаде такая
what is 100% of 100, calculate
сколько будет 100% от 100 посчитай
100% of 100 Yes, calculate using the
100% от 100 Да Посчитай по
formula Well, that will be a different formula,
формуле Ну это уже другая формула будет
yes, a different one, I
да да другая
would like to remember it correctly, 100% of
правильно вспомнить бы её ещё 100% от
let it be 01 I  I'll guess I made a little
пусть будет 01 Я на угад скажу чуть-чуть
mistake come on the comma is a little bit in the wrong
ошиблась давай запятая немного не
place
там
01 No well you're moving
01 Не ну ты не в ту сторону двигаешь
the comma in the wrong
запятую не в ту
direction I don't
сторону Я не знаю
know I don't know I don't know the answer I don't know I don't
мне не знаю не знаю ответ не знаю я не
remember
помню
the formula and if I don't remember it means I don't know it
формулу а не помню значит не знаю это
will be 10  10 100 100% 20 20% of 100 it
будет 10 10 100 100% 20 20% от 100 это ж
was d d a 100 - It is n times more than
было д д а 100 - Это в п раз больше чем
20 So 100% of 100 - it will be 10 10
20 Значит 100% от 100 - это будет 10 10
10 Yes, I understood everything from mathematics very
10 Да всё поняла с математика очень
simply yes And how much will be, for example,
просто да А сколько будет например
60% of  100 now  we
60% от 100 сейчас мы
will learn Let's learn 60% of
научимся Давайте научимся 60% от
six Oh you already know this super Come on 10%
шесть О это уже шаришь супер Давай 10%
of
от
100 Oh super and 1% of 100 how much is 0
100 О супер а 1% от 100 сколько будет 0
0.1 well done you see everything everything is very simple
0,1 молодец всё видишь всё очень просто
yes Learn yes And how much is 1000% of
да Научись да А сколько будет 1000% от
100 zero
100 ноль
comma  I need to move in that direction or
запятая я в ту сторону или
back in the other direction
обратно в другую сторону надо двигать
100 is correct If uh 100% of 100 is
100 правильно Если ээ 100% от 100 - это
10 Then 1000% of 100 is 10 times
10 Значит 1000% от 100 - Это в 10 раз
more is 100 Absolutely correct Yeah
больше - это 100 Абсолютно верно Угу
Right, cool, got it But the tricky one is too,
Правильно круто понял А вот хитро тоже
let's watch it again  so, eh, we've already
давай ещё раз смотре значит э мы уже
discussed 20% of 100 - how much
разбирали 20% от 100 - это сколько
is two times two, and 100% of
будет два два а 100% от
two is already new, yes Question This is not Oh
два это уже новый да Вопрос Это не бы Ой
[music]
[музыка]
well, I'll guess 05 now, let it
а ну я сейчас на угад скажу 05 пусть
be correct 05, you know reverse
будет правильно 05 шаришь обратная
mathematics, that's where it goes, yes  And I just
математика туда идт да А я короче просто
cancel out the zeros 10 and 2 and just divide
нули сокращаются 10 и2 и просто делю
like Although it is
типа Хотя оно
put there I also I also know how to move p
там постави Я тоже я тоже умею двигаю п
and move za absolutely correctly
и двигаю за абсолютно правильно
Yes you remember the multiplication tables from school
Да таблиц умножения помнишь ещё со школы
Oh I remember how I learned it with tears in my
Ох я помню как я её учила со слезами на
eyes Let me even check
глазах Давайте проверю мне даже
interesting Let's do 7 by
интересно Давайте 7 на
8 56 and 7 by 7 49 super Everything is fine with
8 56 а 7 на 7 49 супер Всё нормально у
you yes And 6 by 8 48 everything here you
тебя да А 6 на 8 48 всё тут всё
know everything yes great with percentages I thought a little
знаешь да класс с процентами немножко
you counted for a long time ti Well, that's
задумывалась ты долго считала ти Ну
right counting mathematics I had it for a long time Yeah, I
правильно счита математики давно у меня
got it I even according to it  I miss it I used to
Угу понял Я даже по ней скучаю Я раньше
love math it was my favorite
любила математику это был мой любимый
subject Well, until the tenth grade for sure and I
предмет Ну до десятого класса точно а
studied history Yes but I didn't really like it
изучала Да но я её не особо любила
Because our teacher was so-so
Потому что учитель у нас был Ну так себе
but it was interesting I would have studied it with
но было интересно я бы её с
pleasure if we had a
удовольствием изучала если бы нам её
little more  tell another why why
чуть по-другому расска А почему почему
Napoleon attacked
Наполеон напал на
Crimea in general I am history minus past I am not my own
Крым вообще я история минус мимо я неша
anyway I should know why Napoleon
всё равно должна знать почему Наполеон
attacked Crimea I don't know well the most
напал на Крым Я не знаю ну самое
banal thing there  I wanted to seize the territory I
банальное там територию захватить
don't know right And why
захотел не знаю правильно А почему Ленин
did Lenin oppose
выступил против
Napoleon because the five-year plan in 2 days
Наполеона потому что пятилетку за 2 дня
no seriously Why did Lenin
не ну серьёзно Почему Ленин выступил
oppose
против
Napoleon no here even logically I don't know
Наполеона нет тут даже логически не знаю
how to figure it out because Lenin didn't like the
как додуматься пото что Ленин не любил
French
французов
And he was like yes yes he was ugly
А он такой да да некрасивой он был
against the French  Yes, it's not nice, I
против французов Да некрасиво я вообще
don't think at all that you need to be against
не считаю что нужно быть против
some people, we are all people, we are all one
какого-то народа мы все люди мы все одно
creature, and to be against someone
существо и быть против кого-то потому
because he is such and such a nationality or from
что он такой-то национальности или с
such and such a country is
такой страны это
funny, it turns out that our own people, yes. And why
смешно своих же получается да А почему
did Gorbachev poison Lenin?
Горбачёв отравил Ленина
Well  it's banal I don't know the desire of the authorities
Ну это банально Не знаю желание власти
maybe some right Yes it was
может какое-нибудь правильно Да это было
known their conflict and then he was at the
известно ихний конфликт и он потом на
meal Yes he poisoned Lenin and he still
трапезе Да отравил Ленин до сих пор
lies in the Mausoleum I
лежит Мавзолее
understood
понял
yes And who created
да А кто создал
Ukraine who I don't know it seems to me that the countries
Украину кто я не знаю мне кажется страны
with you were created by themselves somehow  then over
с вами по себе создались как-то со
time, like, the people somehow just
временем типа Просто народ как-то в
turned into some kind of society, and the society
общество какое-то превратился А Общество
turned into a state, like, according to
превратилось в государство как это по
some kind of philosophical thoughts of some kind of
каким-то там философским мыслям каких-то
people, I remember we studied this  did
там людей я помню мы это изучали
someone have some kind of idea about the
какая-то такая мысль у кого-то была о
beginning of the state like okay but for
начале государства типа хорошо а вот
example well this question maybe it's not
например ну такой вопрос может он не
quite correct then but I have to
совсем корректный тогда но я долже
ask do you consider yourself homo sapiens
задать ты считаешь себя гомо сапиен
so in translation it's a reasonable person
сом так в переводе это человек разумный
No no that's not it but who  this is
Да нет это не то а кто это
orientation no homo sapiens is a
ориентация нет гомо сапиенс - это
rational person H sapin is a
человек разумный H сапин это человек
rational person I studied biology I e habilis
разумный я биологию изучала я е хабилис
is a
- это человек
rational person no H sapin habilis
разумный нет H сапин хабилис
I'll even check No this is the one who didn't
Я даже проверю Нет это который не всё
understand everything understood and Sai is already a
понял понял а Sai - это уже человек
rational person translation of some language  then you are
разумный перево какого-то языка то ты
a sapin
сапин
I am a homo sapiens but I am not a homo I understand I
я гомо сапиенс но я не гомо я понял
understand yes And you are a
Понял да А это ты
sapio Do you like smart
сапио Тебе нравится умные
people Yes I like interesting people
люди Да мне нравятся интересные люди у
who have an interesting opinion and with whom you
которых интересное мнение и с которыми
can have an interesting conversation even if
можно интересно поговорить даже если в
I may not agree with something I
чём-то я могу быть не согласна мне
just  I wonder how other people
просто интересно как другие люди
think about what drives them and everything like
размышляют что ими движет и всё как бы
you like guys guys with a
тебе нравятся парни парни с
mathematical mindset
математическим складом ума
Well I don't know what to talk about with them about the
Ну я не знаю о чём с ними говорить о
number Pi that rules
числе Пи которое правит
the world Well you can about  percent talk about
миром Ну можно о процентах поговорить о
percent Well I don't know if there
процентах Ну я не знаю если что-то там
will be something there Mega I wonder how with the number pi
будет Мега Интересно как с числом пи то
then in principle we can talk about
тогда в принципе можно поговорить о
percent Do you really want to talk about
процентах А ты реально хочешь с
the number and the number of pi with a mathematician
математиком число и числе пипа
Well I somehow analyzed it read and
говорить Ну я как-то разбирала читала и
I'm just awesome
я пря офи
is everywhere
есть везде
Absolutely thanks to the number you can
Абсолютно благодаря числу можно ВС
simply do it This is awesome I was totally
просто сделать Это Я вообще
amazed this is cool if it's the same with
офигела это прикольно если тоже самое с
percentages then I want to listen to it I'm
процентами то я хочу это послушать мне
interested and you don't know where in percentages
интересно а ты не знаешь где в процентах
the number Pi pops up
число Пи всплывает
Well if you have
Ну если у тебя есть на
this then tell me a lot
этот то расскажи мно
from us  we'll get the number
от мы получим число
Pi in more detail Well, this needs to be written out
Пи поподробнее Ну это надо расписывать У
I don't have a board now Well, it would be more
меня сейчас доски нету Ну вот было бы
convenient if I wrote it out Well, okay Well, it's
удобнее бы Расписал Ну ладно Ну
cool if you and I were somewhere like this,
прикольно если мы с тобой где-то так
you know, there over a cup of coffee I would
были знаешь там за чашечкой кофе я бы те
draw you here
тут нарисовал
and the mathematician uh proved that for any  x
да математик ээ доказал что при любом x
x about from x about will be the number
x про от x про будет число
Pi Wow
Пи Нифига себе
Yeah, cool I generally also really like the
Да круто Мне вообще ещё очень нравится
theme associated with the film istre yeah Oh, this is
тема связанная с фильмом истр да О это
generally string theory there I love it Yes, this is
вообще теория струн там Я обожаю Да это
my favorite film I love it  I just
мой самый любимый фильм Я его просто
rewatched it 500,000 times I even bought
пересматривала 500.000 раз я даже купила
Stephen Hawking's book I
книгу Стивена Хокинга вот Я хочу её
really want to read it it tells
очень прочитать там как раз рассказано
about everything that was in the film I just don't
про всё что было в фильме просто я не
know it blows my mind I even
знаю мне это так мозг взрывает я я даже
when I watch this film I sometimes even
когда смотрю этот фильм Я иногда даже
cry because like I  it's sad
плачу потому что типа Мне грустно от
that people instead of spending
того что люди вместо того чтобы тратить
money on space exploration spend it on
деньги на Изучение космоса тратят на
some nonsense damn By the way, do you know
какую-то ерунду блин Ты кстати знаешь
that Pythagoras has two theorems that
что у Пифагора есть две теоремы которым
he was known for? In school they only teach one,
он был известен в школе учат только одну
this Pythagorean theorem, there are the catta of the
вот эту теорема Пифагора там катты
hypotenuse. What other is the most famous?
гипотенузы А какая ещё самая известная
but in school
но в школе
the unstudied proved Yes that the diameter of the Circle
неизученный доказал Да что диаметр Круга
is equal to two radii twice the
равен двум радиусам в два раза больше
radius And this is his idea Yes he proved
радиуса А это его мысль Да он доказал
that why don't they say this Well, in
что почему это не говорят это же ну в
school they also
школе тоже же
study equal to two radii Well, in
изучает равно два радиуса Ну вот в
America in America Yes, they teach Yes
Америке в Америке Да вот преподают Да
what is this called the first
что это называется первая теорема
Pythagorean theorem Yes what uh the diameter is twice the
Пифагора Да что ээ диаметр в два раза
radius the
больше радиуса
diameter of the Circle is twice the radius
диаметр Круга в два раза больше радиуса
And in the Soviet post-Soviet school only
А в Советской постсоветской школе только
this Pythagorean theorem that they will roll and they
вот эту теорему Пифагора что прокатят и
say hypotenuse Well  yes, they just say about the diameter,
гипотенузы говорят Ну да про диаметр
like remember, the diameter
просто говорят типа запомните диаметр
is equal to two radii, that's all you need Znara, and he
равен двум радиусам всё надо Зна ра а он
proved it, he proved that it burns for anyone, he
доказал он доказал что у любого он горит
proved it for anyone, he didn't say that
доказал именно у любого не говорил что
believe me, there are these cosines through the sines,
поверьте там через синусы вот эти
yes, he proved that the
косинусы Да он доказал что у любого
diameter of any Circle is twice as big  more than the radius of
Круга диаметр в два раза больше радиуса
y and this and this entailed very large
у и это и это повлекло очень большие
geometric changes then Yes,
геометрические потом изменения Да очень
this theorem was used a lot there and
много эту теорему использовали там и
Newton and Euler and others like that used
Ньютон и Эйлер и нка типа использовали
Yes, so it's
Да так
cool and there is also an inverse
круто причём там есть и обратная
relationship not only that,
зависимость мало того что
as he says, the diameter of each Circle is not the
как он говорит диаметр каждого Круга не
diameter of any  The circle is equal to the doubled
диаметр любого Круга равен удвоенному
radius This is the first version of the theorem and the
радиусу Это первый вариант теоремы а
second And also
второй Да ещё и
that the radius of any circle is equal to
что радиус любого Круга равен
50% of the diameter of the same
50% диаметра этого же
circle such Surprise permutations of
Круга такая Удивите перестановки ме
terms the sum does not change Well not quite
слагаемых сумма не меняется Ну не совсем
yes not quite here you see
да не совсем тут видиш
there through percentages and there through
нем там через проценты а там через
doubling
удвоение
[music  ]
[музыка]
through the
чере
joke mathematics is everywhere Well yes it
прикол математика она всюду Ну да она
is an interesting subject in fact
это интересный предмет на самом деле
that is probably why I loved it it is
поэтому я наверное его и любила он
interesting I liked to calculate there to
интересно мне нравилось вычислять там
count something of course it is a pity we are not  to
что-то считать вот конечно жаль нас не
deepen exactly how it is used in the world, they
углублять именно то как это в мире
just show us
используется нам просто типа показывают
examples of how to solve how it is shown in the world,
как примеры решать как это в мире
this is of course sad because I
показано это конечно грустно потому что
just got out of school and understood where
вот как раз вышла со школы и поняла где
exactly mathematics is used and I was
именно используется математика и я ж
really upset that they didn't tell us this
прямо расстроилась что нам этого не
before Well,
рассказывали раньше Ну
yes  And what did you like most about mathematics
да А что тебе из математики самое больше
in
понравилось в
school? I liked solving equations, all
школе мне нравилось уравнения решать
sorts of different complex easy ones.
очень всякие разные сложные лёгкие там
I loved equations.
вот я любила уравнения
Yeah. And what is the smallest number
Угу А какое самое маленькое число
that exists in nature? Can you
которое В природе существует можешь
name
назвать
the number? The number is the smallest
число именно число самое маленькое
number. That's right. There are no numbers smaller than that. Well done,
число правильно меньше дети числа не
yes.  these are already numbers from
бывает молодец да это цифры уже от
one to nine right I know you know
одного до девяти правильно это я знаю
it Well done And the biggest
шаришь Молодец А самое большое
number
число
Oh there's probably something there already but no
Ой там наверное что-то уже а нет
wait maybe there's some here too to
подождите может тут тоже какая-то есть к
the supply is not the biggest number Just here
подвод не самое большое число Просто тут
I don't even know But definitely not
я уже даже не знаю Но точно не
infinity No, not infinity
бесконечность Нет не бесконечность
of course
конечно
infinity
бесконечность
And I know now or Google or whatever it
А я знаю сейчас или Google или как его
is Google yes the biggest number is
есть Google да самое большое число - это
Google yes Google exactly Google and
Google да Google во точно Google и
Google this is
Google это это
also Euler's theorem Yes that Google is the
тоже теорема Эйлера Да что Google есть
biggest number and Google P 1 this
самым большим числом и Google П 1 это
will already be  that is, before Google If you
уже будет то есть до Гугла Если
add one, everything will be  equal
добавлять единичку будет всё равно
Google nothing That is, this is a number
Google нифига То есть это такое число
that is the very last number in the
которое есть самым последним числом в
calculation Yes, no matter how much you add to it,
исчисления Да ты к нему сколько не
it no longer changes Yeah It's
прибавляй оно уже не изменяется Угу Это
like a cup, if it's full Yes, you
как чаша вот если она наполнена Да ты в
fill it, it will no longer be
неё наполняешь она уже больше не
filled, it's a joke And I
будет будет больше наливаться прикол А я
on the contrary, once upon a time, somewhere, they
наоборот когда-то вот где-то мне
showed me something like A on TikTok, I
показывали типа что-то А в тиктоке
came across something like there was a big number and
попадалось типа вот там большое число и
there were comments, you know Like if you
там комментарии знаете Типа если к нему
add one to it, it’s no longer the biggest
прибавить один это уже не самое большое
number, that’s it Now I didn’t think even more
число это есть Теперь ещё больше я не
like A how  this is explained You
думала типа А как это объясняется Вот вы
explained it to me
мне объяснили
in a cool way that is, it is no longer possible to
прикольно то есть больше уже нельзя его
make it it will be as it is and this is not an
сделать оно как и будет са а это не
added number yes that is what it
прибавляемое число да то есть оно
is called not an added number and how is
называется так не прибавляемое число а
it
как оно
written how is it
записывается как оно
written one with 100 zeros
записывается единица со 100 нулями
Yeah I By the way I heard there is also  about
Угу я Кстати слышала ещё есть про
some number and again in TikTok they
какое-то число и опять же в тиктоке типа
wrote like there If you can remember it
там писали Если вы его сможете запомнить
your brain will collapse into a black
ваш мозг скол апси ется в чёрную
hole I'm even wondering now what it
дыру мне даже интересно сейчас как оно
[the music]
[музыка]
is called and here I am  I also googled it,
называется а вот тут я ещё загуглила тут
there was a plex here, and some other one,
есть был плекс Ещё какой-то
yeah, oh, I probably won't find it anymore. You
Да Ой я уже наверное не найду Это число
have to look for that number on TikTok. Well, that's the
это в тиктоке надо искать Ну короче вот
fact. It's just that it's
как факт Просто оно там как-то
not called anything else there, not Google anymore, but
по-другому не называется не Google уже а
something else.  his
как-то по-другому его
Yeah I don't remember anymore
Угу Я уже не помню
And the question Look, if we
А вопрос Вот смотри если мы к число
add one to the number Google, we'll also get
Google добавим единичку получится тоже
the number Google So yeah,
число Google Так угу
and if we subtract one from it, what
а если мы от него отнимем единичку что
[music]
[музыка]
will be, it will also be
будет тоже будет
Google Yes, why Yes, because it's
Google Да почему Да а потому что это
such a number if already We  we got into it then
такое число если уже Мы в него попали то
No matter how much we added to it,
Сколько бы мы к нему не прибавляли
no matter how much we subtracted, no matter how much we divided, it doesn't
сколько не отнимали не делили не
multiply Well, it's constant, that is, yes, a
умножается А ну вот оно постоянно то
constant my number in mathematics is called
констан мо число в математике называется
If you got there, added, added, you
Если вы дошли добавили добавили у вас
got Bul Yes, you already
получилось Бул Да вы уже сколько к нему
don't add to it how much  no matter
не добавляете сколько ней отнимать
how much you subtract, no matter how much you multiply, no matter how much you divide, even by
сколько не умножать и не делить даже на
zero, if you multiply everything, it doesn't
ноль если будешь умножать всё он не
change. This is Google. Yeah. This is
меняется Это Google Угу Это как каменное
called a stone number. Where in the world is it
число такое называется А где оно в мире
used at all? Is it used
используется вообще оно используется
somehow? Yes, in quantum cybernetics.
както это да в квантовой кибернетике вот
quantum computers Where do they have
квантовые компьютеры Да где у них там
these quantum processors there is a
вот эти квантовые процессоры там
huge amount of calculations yes uh
огромнейшее количество вычислений да э-э
no processor can have
не может ни один процессор иметь
more calculations than Google operations per
вычисление больше Google операции в
second physically can't
секунду физически не может прикол
funny I wonder about and in mathematics for example uh
Интересно по а по математике например ээ
what else do you know what
что вы знаете ещё какие-то какие
numbers Well the number Pi the number e
числа Ну число Пи число е
but I don't know Well maybe you can tell me maybe I'll remember
а не знаю Ну может скажете может вспомню
Well what first comes to mind is
Ну так то что первое на ум приходит
good And what do you know about the features of numbers
хорошо А какие знаете особенности чисел
zero and
ноль и
one can't be divided by zero in school and in
оди на ноль делить нельзя в школе а в
university higher mathematics It turns out
универе высшей математике Оказывается
you can you can yes
можно можно да
but I don't know Well  there were some
а не знаю Ну что-то были какие-то
jokes I remember we studied but you have
приколы Я помню мы учили но у вас есть
higher mathematics in
высшая математика на
philology no we don't have it it's just like
филологии нет у нас нет это просто как
if you enter a university in
если в ВУЗ поступишь на математический
some mathematics department then it will be
какой-нибудь факультет то там будет
studied there But we had it we didn't
изучаться Но у нас и была у нас это не
higher mathematics was called but tenth
высшая математика называлась но десятый
eleventh grade We studied specialized
одиннадцатый класс Мы изучали профильную
mathematics there like slightly
математику там типа чуть
in-depth
углубленные
knowledge But if we were
знания Но если бы мы это время
preparing for the Unified State Exam at that time,
готовились к ЕГЭ
therefore specialized mathematics I so  and I didn't
поэтому профильную математику я так и не
study it properly I got it And here's another
изучала как надо понял А ещё вот
interesting feature of numbers if we
интересная особенность чисел если мы
take the number
возьмём число
777 and we always add four to it
777 так и будем добавлять к нему четыре
Yes Yeah We'll never get
всегда Да Угу Мы никогда не получим
a number that's divisible by
число которое делится на
two This is also Vieta's theorem one of
два Вот это тоже теорема Виета одна из
Vieta's theorems What is the number 777
теорем Виета Да что число 777 оно
special no matter how many fours you add to it
особенное сколько к нему не добавлять
Yes adding even is
четвёрки Да добавлять чет это именно
only 777 Yes 777 it works yes if
только 777 Да 777 это работает да если
you don't add fours to it we
сколько к нему не добавлять четвёрки мы
won't be able to get a number that is divisible
не сможем получить число которое делится
by D joke Well try 777 yes plus
на Д прикол Ну вот попробуй 777 да плюс
4 What is
4 Сколько будет
781 Yes it is not divisible by  two more plus 4 785 is
781 Да не делится на два ещё плюс 4 785
not divisible by D another bee 89 Yes this Dasha will
не делится на Д ещё пче 89 Да это Даше
never be able to get a number that is
никогда не сможем получить число которое
divisible by Da Joke Well it will always be
делится на Да Прикол Ну оно будет всегда
yes it turns out it will end in
да получается оно будет оканчиваться на
1 5
1 5
9 3 7 different Yes and more than that even if
9 3 7 разные Да и больше того даже если
we are from 777  we will subtract fours We will
мы от 777 будем отнимать четвёрки Мы
also not get a number,
тоже ни получим число вот
try it Well, yes, there it will be 773
попробуй Ну да там будет получается 773
then 769 then
потом 769 потом
761 and then
761 и потом
757 again Yes, we will never get a number Well,
757 опять Да никогда не получим число Ну
yes, it will always end in odd numbers
да оно будет всё время на нечётные числа
Yes, here is the peculiarity of the number
оканчиваться Да вот э особенность числа
777, this is the theorem of the four or the theorem
777 это э теорема четвёрки или теорема
or the second theorem of Vieta
или вторая теорема Виета
is called a joke, it's
называется прикол это
interesting what other interesting numbers do you
интересно какие ещё ты интересные числа
know  Well, that's all I say
знаешь Ну вот говорю только так
and they don't tell us anything like that. There's
и всё нам ничего не рассказывают такого
also this cool
Есть ещё такое есть такая прикольная
thing called a digital root. Do you know
штука называется цифровой корень знаешь
what a digital
что такое цифровой
root is? Well, if it can be
корень Ну если графически может
explained graphically, maybe Remember, don't look. If
объяснить может Вспомни не смотри если
we take a number, add all its digits,
мы возьмём число добавим его все цифры
then the number that  it will work
так потом у того числа которое получится
again we will add all the numbers yes And so
снова добавим все цифры да И так дальше
we will continue forever There will be only
будем продолжать всегда Останется только
one number left Imagine, let's take for example
одна цифра Прикинь вот возьмём например
888 Yeah add 8 + 8 + 8
888 Угу добав 8 + 8 + 8
how much is 3 by 8 how much is 24 24 now
сколько 3 на 8 сколько это 24 24 теперь
2 + 4 How much is six p one
2 + 4 Сколько шесть п осталась одна
number left but here's what  joke and
цифра а вот в чём прикол а
VOM singing is deste Only one
ВОМ поя это десте Останется только одна
fra will remain, that is, it doesn't matter how many there will be
фра то есть неважно сколько там будет
numbers, for example, look at 1230,
чисел хоть возьмём например смотри 1230
there are 9, for example,
там 9 Да например
1239, let's
1239 Давай
add 1 + 2 + 3
добав 1 + 2 + 3
+9, 1 + 2 + 3, it turns out 3 + 3, 6, 15, 1 + 5,
+9 1 + 2 + 3 получается 3 + 3 6 15 1 + 5
6, okay,
6 хорошо
because you'll add all its digits to the number
дабо добавишь все его цифры у того числа
that you get, you'll add more digits
что получится ещё добавишь цифры ещё так
so if you repeat it like this always there will
ещё вот если так повторять всегда
be only one digit left imagine
Останется только одна цифра Прикинь
yeah yeah well that's if you add them in order
Угу Ну это если их по порядку складывать
yeah but if you start adding them from the ends the
да А если их типа с концов начинать
trick is shorter the trick of this
складывать фишка короче фишка этого
digital root yeah anyway there
цифрового кореня Да всё равно один да
will be one anyway for example
будет по-любому например
look let's
смотри
take
возьмём
378 yeah yeah yeah  we add 3 + 7 p 8 we get
378 да Угу мы сложим 3 + 7 п 8 получится
18 and 8 + 7 + 3 we get 18 and that is
18 и 8 + 7 + 3 получится 18 и то есть
this this From the rearrangement of me this is the magic of the
это это От перестановки ме это магия
digital root yes yes I understand yes it's
цифрового корня да да понятно да
funny Well this is interesting and it turns out
прикол Ну это интересно и получается
that as if this digital ko
что как бы у этого цифрового ко никогда
can never have a number  you'll get zero Yeah, what
не может цифра ноль получиться Угу Какое
number would you take other than zero, but you won't
бы число кроме нуля ты взяла Да не
get the number zero  one digit Stay
получится цифра ноль одна цифра Остане
from o to
от о до
de Yeah Well, yes, it's impossible for
де Угу Ну это да это невозможно чтобы
zero to be obtained so that Zero it must be the
ноль получился то чтобы Ноль это надо
other way around Subtract Yeah, if it works out at all
наоборот Вычитать Угу ели вообще так
and here's another problem,
получится а ещё такая вот задача
there's a unit Yeah, we multiply it by two and
э есть единичка Да мы её умножаем на два
get 2, we also multiply it by two and
получается 2 ещё умножаем на два
get 4  we also multiply by two and
получается 4 ещё умножаем на два
get 8 Yes How many times do we need to
получается 8 Да Сколько раз надо
multiply by two so that the number is divisible
умножить так на два чтобы число делилось
by 10
на 10
so that we multiply 10 times how many
чтобы ну 10 раз умножить сколько нам
twos do we need to multiply so that they are
перемножить двоек нужно чтобы они
divisible by
разделились на
ten twos multiply 2 by 2 by 2 by
десят двоек перемножить 2 у 2 на 2 на 2
2 by 2 so that in the end  got
На 2 чтобы в конце получился
zero this is a power Yes probably some
ноли это степень Да наверно какой-нибудь
D To what power is it necessary for it to be divisible
Д В какой степени надо чтобы разделилось
by 10
на 10
without a remainder It seems to me Well what
без остатка Мне кажется Ну что после
was after the decimal point It seems to me that the magic of
запятой был Мне кажется так вот магия
two is that there is no power of
двойки в том что не существует степени
two such that it is divisible by 10
двойки такой чтобы она делилась на 10
this is a unique property  twos yes it's
вот это уникальное свойство двойки да
only with two so yes only with
это только с двойкой так да только с
two that two to any power is not
двойкой что двойка в любой степени не
divisible by
делится на
10  It's impossible to pick up
10 Нифига себе невозможно подобрать
Why didn't they tell us this at school?
Почему нам этого в школе не
I went to math with pleasure even more. We
математику ходила Очень много у нас
had a very good math teacher. I remembered a lot. Well,
был я вот очень много запомнил Ну вот у
we also have a good teacher, but he's good in
нас тоже хороший учитель но он хороший в
terms of preparing for exams. And as a
плане подготовки к экзаменам А как
subject  study Well, we didn't really study it
предмет изучать Так мы его и не изучали
Well, this is generally the case in all of our
толком Ну это так вообще во всех у нас
Russian schools It seems to me
российских школах Мне кажется во многих
that in many of them they neglect studying the subject in some
что на изучение предмета именно как-то
interesting, cool, awesome way in the
интересно круто классно забивают в
eighth grade Well, let's see, either you
восьмом классе Ну давай посмотрим или ты
or you remembered the percentage, what is
или ты запомнила процент сколько будет
20%  from
20% от
100 Damn 20% d you remember correctly super and
100 Блин 20% д правильно помнишь супер а
100% from
100% от
and now 10 everything is correct on 10 five times you
а сейчас 10 всё правильно на 10 пять раз
will be everything super percentages you have mastered
будешь всё супер проценты ты освоила у
me well done you remembered Yes I got it
меня молодец запомнила Да
Yeah cool not cool
понял Угу класс не прикольно
cool And what numbers do you know
прикольно А какие ты цифры знаешь
how many numbers Do you know yes  1 2 3 4 5 6 7
сколько цифр Ты знаешь да 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 nine digits everything exists true yes
8 9 девять цифр всё существует правда да
well done that's
молодец
right and zero is not a
правильно а ноль не есть
digit no that's right there is more in the
цифрой нет правильно есть ещё ещё в
first  in class they teach yes Children that a zero is
первом классе учат да Дети что нолик -
not a Number is a separate symbol
это не есть Цифра это отдельный значок
that is not a number the numbers are only from
который не есть цифры цифры только от
one to nine correctly there are only
одного до девяти правильно цифр всего
nine numbers yes
девять да
yes because you can add a word minus to a number How is it
да потому что к цифре можно Как
determined you can add a word minus to a number
определяется к цифре можно приписать сло
Yes -1 -2 -3  and mi 0 can't be
минус Да -1 -2 -3 а ми 0 не можно
assigned True Well yes there is no such thing that
приписать Правда Ну да такого нет то
is there is p1 mi1 and zero can't be
есть есть п1 ми1 а ноль не может быть
plus but minus Yes it can't be plus
плюс но мину Да он не может быть плюс
minus it is what it is such is a
минус он какой есть такой есть точка
reference point it is not a number but it is somehow different
отчёта он не цифр а он как-то по-другому
-my opinion it's called something like
по-моему называется типа
yes So I'd like to remember that
да Так вот вспомнить бы ещё вот я как
I was just thinking that you would tell me because
раз таки думала вы мне скажете пото что
I don't remember what it's called Well,
я не помню как называется ну давай
think about it, you'll remember What is the name of a non-
подумай ты вспомнишь Как называется не
digit, eh, but Well, I remember some terms, a
цифра э но Ну я помню какие-то термины
natural, non-natural
натуральное не натуральное
number Oh, I  I'm starting to remember Now
число Ой я начинаю вспоминать Сейчас
wait What is it
подождите Как
called it was called something like that
называется она ж как-то называлось
Lord
Господи
from Zro not the same yes Zro Well this is this is
з Зро не так же да Зро Ну это это это же
where it came from Yes and it went to the casino Yes it went
оттуда пошло Да и в казино типа пошло Да
to the casino and to the English language not
в казино и в английский язык пошло не
it Zro I know that yes but  it's just that in
оно Зро это я знаю да но просто нам на
math they told us something different
математике как-то по-другому ещё
Zro it was called
говорили Зро оно называлось
Zro Well zero is that yes I
Зро Ну зеро это да это я
know that it's exactly like that in casinos What's
знаю это же в казино так именно Да что
different from the others a special number it's
отличается от других особенная цифра она
not even a number it's Zero
даже не цифра она Зеро
Well they also write something neutral here
Ну какой-то тут ещё пишут нейтральный
element is not so I don't remember
элемент это не так Я не помню
how they used to say
как типа говорили
an
целое
integer just an
число просто целое
integer I understood which is neither positive nor
число понял которое не положительно не
negative In short I don't know but we
отрицательно Короче я не знаю но мы его
didn't call it Zro somehow differently that
не Зро назвали как-то по-другому то что
Zro is also known this Poti zero zero they
Зро тоже зна это Поти
don't say zero they say zero  Yeah, I
зеро ноль не говорят говорят зеро Угу
got it, what else? But what are
прикол понял какие ещё А вот что такое
natural
натуральные
numbers? Natural numbers that Well,
числа натуральные числа которые Ну у
I have several
меня несколько
options Well, No, most likely one is
вариантов ну Нет скорее всего один так
positive, it's clear which one plus a
положительно это понятно который плюс
natural number is probably the one that can be
натуральное число - это наверное которое
divided without a remainder, like yes, that's right,
делится без остатка типа да правильно
which one is without a comma and a fraction there, yes,
которая без запятой и дроби там да
and  what are numbers with fractions called with
а как с дробями называются числа с
[music]
[музыка]
commas Well, not a whole Well, I don't know like
запятыми Ну не целая Ну я не знаю типа
decimal fractions are
десятичные дроби
correct And what are numbers with two
правильно А как называется числа с двумя
commas called with two Yes, there are two commas,
запятыми с двумя Да есть две запятые ещё
yes No way, I don't know that Yes
да Нифига себе не не знаю такого Да
you know anyway No we
по-любому знаешь Нет мы двух запятых не
haven't gone through two commas this is called
проходили это называется
a hundred more digits and again a comma yes yes yes
соточка ещё цифры и опять запятая да да
that's it Well what are hundredths I know
да это оно А ну то что соты это я знаю
how they explained to us there is a zero before
нам как объясняли вот есть ноль до
the comma and then if one digit then it's a
запятой и потом если одна цифра то это
decimal if but and  some other Number
десятичная если но и ещ какая-то Цифра
is already if But this is a
это уже если Но это
dro with one comma with two commas -
дро с одной запятой с двумя запятыми -
these are juicy fractions with three commas - these are
это сочные дроби с тремя запятыми - это
thousandths
тысячные
fractions maybe there without commas And how many
дроби может там без запятых А сколько
zeros after the decimal point not commas
нулей после запятой не не запятые
commas exactly Yes this is a degree look the
запятые именно Да это степень смотри
idea is that  10 to the power of the number of
идея в том что 10 в степени количества
these commas Oh, you dropped something Yes,
этих запятых Ой у тебя что-то упало Да у
my stand fell I understand And who do you
меня подставка упала понял А как ты
think Crimea is
считаешь чей Крым
Crimea oh well officially Russia But I don't
Крым ой ну официально Россия А так не
know Well, you have to look at history
знаю Ну это из истории надо смотреть
from which territory it
изначально он вообще с какой территории
was taken from Well, on  what territory
был взят Ну на какой территории
was it located in this is necessary according to history but at the
находился это надо по истории смо но на
moment in
данный момент
Russia and in general whose was it Well I say
России а вообще чей он был Ну я говорю
You need to read
Надо почитать
history initially what
историю изначально территория какого
state's territory was it
государства это была
Well initially it's no no come on You  in your own
Ну изначально это нене давай Ты своими
words
словами
say I don't know
скажи я не знаю
initially Well you will probably say
изначально Ну вы скажете наверное
initially
изначально
Ukraine is not and Napoleon
Украина нет а Наполеона
was France Okay then you didn't guess
был Франция Окей тогда не угадала
and Crimea in the first half of the 1st century of our era
а Крым в первой половине I века нашей
[music]
[музыка]
by the ancient Greeks Greek yes
эры древними греками греки греческий да
that is to say we need to give Crimea to the Greeks
то есть надо отдать грекам в Крым грекам
where do they need Crimea  and it seems to me that it is not
куда им Крым и мне кажется он нафиг не
needed at all but listen Ali you can Then divide the whole world
нужен а слушай Али можно Тогда весь мир
Because
делить Потому что
if you can do a little bit of math you do
если с математикой немножко можешь ты
n't know everything there But with linguistics
там не всё знать Да а вот с лингвистикой
How many letters are in the Russian
Сколько букв в русском
alphabet 32 ​​let it be correct 32 like
алфавите 32 пусть будет правильно 32 как
teeth Well yes 34 or 32 32  not
зубов Ну да 34 или 32 32 не
34 Yes I teased you that like teeth like
34 Да я тебя подколол что как зубов типа
3 And there are 34 34 letters Yes yes I always
3 А их 34 34 буквы Да да Вот я вечно зы
zybayu I always have like 32 33 34 I
баю У меня всё время типа 32 33 34 я
clearly always forget the number and 34
чётко количество всё время забываю а 34
And how many cases are there in the Russian language
А сколько падежей в русском языке
cases it turns out
падежей это получается
nominative accusative  genitive
именительный винительный родительный
dative proposed eh and I
дательный предложенный э
think some other Ivan gave birth
ещё по-моему какой-то так Иван родил
the girl ordered to drag the diaper
девчонку велел тащить пелёнку
six six cases this is how we were taught at
шесть шесть падежей это Нас так учили в
school Ivan this is nominative gave birth
школе Иван это именительный родил
genitive no Ivan gave birth to a girl
родительный нет Иван родил девчонку
dative ordered accusative drag
дательный велел винительный тащить
instrumental diaper
творительный пелёнку
prepositional This is how we remembered cases
предложный Это мы так запоминали падежи
understood
понял
interesting cool And what are the
интересно прикольно А какие послед Какие
last three letters of the Russian alphabet
последние три буквы русского алфавита
eyu I am correct a  before the
эю я правильно а перед
soft
э мягкий
sign э
знак
Well done then ы before then the hard sign
Молодец потом ы перед потом твёрдый знак
before Well and so on Well I know the alphabet
перед Ну и так далее Ну я алфавит знаю
I can
могу
recite yes Well you know all three four letters of the
зачитать да Ну все три четыре буквы
alphabet yes AB vgd and ЖЗ and short
алфавита знаешь да АБ вгд и ЖЗ и кратк
MN o ufkh t Verty sign and soft sign ey ya
МН о уфх т Верты знак и мягкий знак эю я
a zadom  forward you can
а задом наперёд сможешь
backwards Yeah right that's necessary it will be
задом наперёд Да ну это надо это будет
slower Come on
медленнее Давай
A I yu y soft sign y hard
А я ю ы мягкий знак ы твёрдый
sign
знак
cha sha che
ча ша че
[music]
[музыка]
e ch ts f kh u no
э ч ц ф х у нет
x I say it will be it will
х Я говорю это будет это дольше
be longer well x f u
будет ну х ф у
T
Т
SR
СР
O
О
no  Okay, okay, in short, it's hard.  it's
нет Ладно ладно короче это тяжело это
hard yeah well usually no one even
тяже да ну обычно никто и задом наперёд
reads backwards Well yes backwards Yes it's
не читается Ну да задом наперёд Да
harder
тяжелее
Yeah And some I can just read words backwards
Угу А какие-то я могу просто слова задом
It's a very difficult skill
читать Это очень сложный навык
Read the word backwards
Прочитай назад слово
yukh I won't you see you can't read Well
юх не буду видишь не можешь читать Да ну
I won't read that  Read the word
это я не буду читать Прочитай слово
Putin
Путин
back Putin no
назад Путин нету
no and the word Russia Read
нету а слово Россия Прочитай
back me and sor me and sor yes
назад я и сор я и сор да
and with geography how are
а с географией как у
you Well you can play around
тебя Ну можно поиграться
I understand why Yes why in 1917
понял почему Да почему в 1917 году
Australia was renamed
Австралию переименовали в
Austria I think you're kidding Come on
Австрию помоему Вы прикалываетесь Да
these are two different states
ладно этоже два разных государства
right right  right how is the
правильно правильно правильно как
capital of Austria called
столица Австрии называется
Austria gosh Oh
Австрия гос Ой
now
сейчас
Austria for me for some reason
Австрия у меня почему-то
this damn thing is connected with musicians immediately
этот блин связанная с музыкантами сразу
like with some composers that is
типа с композиторами какими-то то есть
who is
там кто
there Bach or who lived there Hungary or
там Бах там или кто там жил Венгрия
something I don't know
какая-нибудь я не знаю
how No no No now  what is
как Нет не Нет сейчас как называется
this year called AST
этот год АСТ
buda buda buda
буда буда буда
buda Budapest Budapest is correct
буда Будапешт Будапешт правильно
Budapest so good yes the capital of
Будапешт так хорошо да столица
Norway
Норвегии
Norway  I don't
Норвегии не
know
знаю
Norway Stockholm Stockholm is right
Норвегия Стокгольм Стокгольм правильно
Yes the capital of Germany Well you know that
Да столица Германии Ну это ты знаешь
No I don't know that Zurich Zurich Zurich the
се Нет это я не знаю Цюрих Цюрих Цюрих
capital Yeah Well
столица Ага Так ну столицу Франции
you know the capital of France France Paris Not Paris - It's one
знаешь Франция Париж Не Париж - Это один
of the largest cities in France And the
из самых больших городов Франции А
capital is a scam
столица это обманка
damn not me  geography is bad Milan
блин не у меня с географией плохо Милан
what is this Bru Bryuse Brussel Brussel the capital of
ка это Брю Брюсе брюсель брюсель столица
France Brule is right Yes I got it the capital of
Франции брюль правильно Да понял столица
Italy Damn well I remember we
Италии Да блин ну я же помню мы это
learned that
учили
M no no mi you called her Mila and Milan
М не не ми ты её называла Мила а Милан
Milan yes Milan the capital of Italy Okay got
Милан да Милан столица Италии О'кей
it the capital of
понял столица
Poland
Польши
Warsaw you guessed right
Варшава ты угадала
Well done Well I wanted to go there for a
Молодец Ну я туда поехать хотела на
concert but unfortunately our
концерт но к сожалению нам закрыты
borders are closed and I'm too lazy to get a multiple entry visa I wo
границы а получать мультивиза Мне лень у
n't be able to do it well the capital of
меня не получится хорошо столица
Great Britain Great Britain is Great
Великобритании Великобритания это Great
BR it's London like there all this stuff
BR это Лондон типа там вот это вот всё
lon the
lon the
Cap is studied in English lessons
Cap на уроках английского языка изучают
like that and the capital of Great Britain  what do you
так а столица Великобритании какая
mean this is another country or something I
В смысле это что другая страна что ли Я
thought
думала
this is England this is England London is the capital of
это это Англия это Англия Лондон столица
England and Great Britain is another
Англии а Великобритании так это другая
country Well it turns out I'm not a big fan of geography Great
страна Ну я получается в географии не
Britain is included
бум-бум в Великобританию входят
Scotland England
Шотландия Англия
UK Northern Ireland y yes
UK Северная Ирландия у да
Yes Great Britain unites here Great
Да Великобритания объединяет вот
Britain unites in UK Yes uned
Великобритания объединяет в UK Да uned
kindom that's why I that there is no such
киндом вот поэтому я что нет такой
country Because it is not a country it is a
страны Потому что это не страна это
union it turns out right yes then
объединение получается правильно да то
Great Britain is a country this capital
Великобритании страна этот столица
what will England be You know you
какая будет Англия Ты знаешь ты
know where I know  remember there is
знае отку Я знаю пом
also a football club such as Manche
ещё футбольный клуб такой есть
Manchester City Manchester Manchester
манче Манчестер Сити Манчестер Манчестер
Yes Manchester is the capital of
Да Манчестер - это столица
Great Britain Yes well done Yeah the capital of
Великобритании Да молодец Ага столица
Spain is Kaka the capital of Brazil Brazil is
Испании кака столица Бразилии Бразилия
right and the capital of Tunisia is Tunisia Algeria
правильно а столица Туниса Тунис Алжира
Algeria yes yes And the USA has pages oh page
Алжир да да А у США страниц ой страница
damn the capital is not New York but  Washington you
блин столица не нью-йорк а Вашингтон
know Well done And what is the capital of Spain
шаришь Молодец А у Испании столица какая
Riga let it be correct Riga
Испании Рига пусть будет правильно Рига
You knew that you knew
Ты это знала ты знала
knew understood also there it is known
знала понял ещё там известно это вот
this well the king of Spain like yes he also
этот ну король Испании типа да он ещё
has the title of Prince of
имеет титул князь
Riga and maybe you have
Рижский и и Может у вас есть продаются
Riga sprats for sale this is also from  Spain is very
рижские шпроты это тоже из Испании очень
famous did not notice did not pay attention
извест не замечала не обращала
[music]
[музыка]
faces of the United Arab Emirates this is not
внимания лица Арабских Эмиратов это не
Dubai And Abu Dhabi yes yes I
Дубай А абу-даби да
also know about A maybe you know Nuno  it's
да тоже шарю по А может знаешь нуно это
difficult at all the capital of
сложно вообще столица
Estonia M now Estonia This is where Latvia
Эстонии М сейчас Эстония Это где Латвия
Lithuania we this this I definitely learned m
Литва мы это это я точно учила м
a Can you give me a hint the first letter vi
а Можно первую букву
Vil vi vi
Виль ви ви
Vil okay No I won't say
Виль ладно Нет не скажу
Vilnius and Estonia isn't Vilnius
Вильнюс а Эстонии разве Вильнюс - это не
Lithuania Latvia ah ugh Vilnius is Lithuania
Литва Латвия а тьфу Вильнюс - это Литва
a  Estonia vilno
а Эстония вильно
vilno vilno
вильно вильно
No, you don't spy, you
Да не ты не подсматривать ты сейчас
'll spy now when I
будешь подсматривать когда я тебя буду
ask you not I'm just looking this is Lithuania
спрашивать не я просто смотрю это Литва
or Latvia here Latvia is Riga and Lithuania
или Латвия вот Латвия - Это Рига а Литва
is Vilnius got it So stop Riga it
- это Вильнюс понял Так стоп Рига это же
was Spain not Riga - it's Latvia So  you
была Испания не Рига - это Латвия Так ты
said that Spain is the capital of Spain
же говорила что Испания столица Испании
Riga Spain No I said Rome oh no
Рига Испания Нет я говорила Рим ой нет
what did I say
что я сказала
and I don't remember what I
а я не помню уже что
said Spain at all where
сказала Испания вообще где
is
находится
ses Riga And how so and you confirmed
сес Рига А как так а вы подтвердили
So you also don't know I didn't know I didn't
Значит тоже не знаете я не знал я не
know Yes I guessed  that's it,
знал Да я угадывал вот так
okay, well, let's check further.
вот ну ладно Ну давайте дальше проверять
Pony is good,
Поня хорош
come on, maybe it's not only
давай а может это может не только
geography. What else?  in what subjects are you
географии Какие ещё в каких предметах Ты
still
ещё
strong Well
сильна Ну может
maybe in social studies I took the Unified State Exam in
быть в обществознании я ЕГЭ сдавала по
social studies Well literature maybe a
обществознанию Ну литература может
little bit in literature okay Okay good
чуть-чуть по литературе окей Окей хорошо
but I'm not saying that I'm strong No I'm not
но я не говорю что я сильна Нет я не
strong I just know a little bit what
сильна просто чуть-чуть знаю какое
work Taras
произведение написал Тарас
Bulba wrote That's not  produced this is not the author this is the
Бульба Это не произведе это не автор это
work itself correctly wrote
произведение правильно написал
it Tolstoy or
Его Толстой или
Dostoevsky Dostoevsky Dostoevsky Yes
Достоевский Достоевский Достоевский Да
Dostoevsky And I wanted to say it
Достоевский А я хотела его сказать
by the way but I said something Who wrote
кстати но я что-то за гово Кто написал
Mumu
Муму
Mumu this what's his name it is Tyutchev no Tyutchev is
Муму этот как его это Тютчев нет Тютчев
correct Tyutchev yes tchev yes he also
правильно Тютчев да тчев да он ещё также
wrote  I love thunderstorms in early May yeah Yeah
писал Люблю грозу в начале мая да Угу
got it I know I really like this piece
понял Я знаю это произведение очень
I remember exactly I love thunderstorms
нравится Я помню вот именно Люблю грозу
in early May IOC wrote who wrote Who
в начале мая МОК написа кто написа Кто
wrote Woe from Wit Woe from Wit This is my
написал Горе от ума горя ума Это моё
favorite piece one of my favorite
любимое произведение одно из любимых
pieces Chekhov Chekhov is
произведений сеча че Чехов Чехов
right I adore Woe  from the mind Yes who
правильно Я обожаю Горе от ума Да кто
wrote
написал
the inspector Gogol correctly I like it not
ревизор Гоголь правильно мне нравится не
My scene at the end is cool so good  Who
Моя сцена в конце крутая так хорошо Кто
wrote
написал
Evenings on a Farm Near
Вечера на хуторе близ
Dikanka Oh
Диканьки О
Lord
Господи
blika Tolstoy Tolstoy Tolstoy
блика Толстой Толстой Толстой правильно
got it right And who wrote War and
понял так А кто написал Война и
Peace Tolstoy
мир Толстой
is right too yes So and who wrote
правильно тоже да Так а кто написал
Now now now now M what else
Сейчас сейчас сейчас сейчас М что ещё
is there So so
такое есть Так так
so who wrote The Tale of Tsar
так кто написал Сказку о царе
Saltan and the tale  about the fisherman and the goldfish
Салтане и сказку о рыбаке и золотой
Pushkin No no no what are you talking about Pushkin Pushkin
Пушкин Нет нет нет ты что Пушкин Пушкин
about the bow
про луко
oh yeah Lord goldfish I can
а ну это да Господи золотой рыбки я могу
just list who I know damn
просто перечислять кого знаю блин
yeah and Yesenin what Yesenin Yes the tale of the fisherman
есе а Есенин что Есенин Да сказку рыбаке
goldfish yeah And what what else have you read
золотой рыб есе А что что ты ещё читала
from literature Well there you go  I really
из литературы Ну вот мне очень
like
нравится стихотворение
Mandelstam's poem, I think his
Мандельштама по-моему так его
last name was Notre Dame,
фамилия Нотердам
I even remember the quatrain I learned
вот я даже помню четверостишие выучила
like But the more attentively and firmly
типа Но чем внимательнее и тверды
Notre Dame I looked at your ribs, the more
Нотердам твои рассматривал я рёбра тем
often I think I'm not some kind of memory for
чаще думаю я из памяти не какой-то там
long and I'll someday
недолго и я когда-нибудь прекрасное
create something beautiful, in short, about  it's just this
создам короче про как раз таки вот этот
cathedral, the Temple that Notre Dame built and the
собор Храм который построен Нотердам и
lyrical hero there  inspired by the
типа лирический герой там вдохновляется
architect who created such a
архитектором который создал такое
building and once wanted to do the same thing
строение и когда-то хотел тоже бы такое
sotka type about himself writes through le What is
соть типа про себя пишет через ле Какое
good Which of the works of Alexander
хорошо Какое из произведений Александра
Prokhorov You
Прохорова Ты
know I think I know 100% yes yes you
знаешь мне кажется я 100% знаю да да
know we went through several at school I
знаешь проходили в школе несколько я
Pronya Alexander
Проня Александра
Prokhorov Well I probably  I won't tell you let's
Прохорова Ну я наверное не скажу давай
think about it somehow I don't know maybe
подумай как-нибудь не знаю можно
some hints Red
подсказок Красное
and red and white only red and Czech Republic red and
и красное и белое толь крас и ЧР крас и
Czech Republic Czech Republic Yes this is the
ЧР ЧР Да это
most famous work by Alexandra Prokhorov
известнейшие Александра Прохорова
I also like the
произведение мне ещё нравится
work by Anna Akhmatova requiem I
произведение Анны Ахматова рекви
think
по-моему
[music]
[музыка]
is called or Or am I wrong Well there
называется или Или я ошибаюсь Ну там
in short something here and the masters Margarita
короче что-то вот а мастеры Маргарита
Who
Кто
wrote damn now Wait masters
написал блин сечас Подождите мастера
Margarita Well this is Well my God this is
Маргарита Ну это же Ну Господи это же
also Alexander Prokhorov Prokhorov too
тоже Александр Прохоров Прохоров тоже
Prokhorov Prokhorov the most famous here are the
Прохоров Прохоров известнейшие вот
masters Margarita Red and black this is And the
мастеры Маргарита Красная и чёрная это И
third work of Alexander Prokhorov
третье произведение Александра Прохорова
You also
Вы ещё
know The Headless Horseman The Headless Horseman
знае Всадник без головы Всадник без
heads Wow I know these works
головы Нифига себе Я эти произведения
but I don't  I knew that he was the Master
знаю но я не знала что он да Мастере
Margarita Yes red and black and the
Маргарита Да красный и чёрный и Всадник
Headless Horseman The Headless Horseman is the
без головы Всадник без головы - это
most popular work of Alexander
самое популярное произведение Александра
Prokhorov known all over the world
Прохорова известно во всём мире
translated into different languages ​​and so on
переводится на разные языки и так дальше
Yes cool I also like Oblomov
Да круто Мне вот ещё нравится Обломов
the work is also my
произведение тоже моя
favorite Griboyedov in my opinion
любимое Грибоедов по-моему
wrote you know how by the way Alexander
написал знаете как кстати умер Александр
Prokhorov died how A didn't you study at
Прохоров как А вы не учили в
school or did you study and I missed it I understood he
школе или учили а я пропустила понял он
died during the writing of the work seriously Yes during what
умер серьёзно Да во время какого
Margarita some master Margarita
Маргарита какая-нибудь мастера Маргарита
no no this is
не не это
written cool I also like Dead Souls
написаны прикольно мне ещё Мёртвый души
at Go his  shot with a crossbow
нравится у Go его застрелили из арбалета
I also
мне ещё
like with a crossbow Shoot Alexander
нравится с арбалета Застрели Александра
Prokhorov Yes, shot with a crossbow
Прохорова Да из арбалета застрелили
Wow, by the way, here's an interesting fact I
кстати вот интересный факт я
somehow thought about
как-то короче задумывалась по поводу
Pushkin's death and even made my own
смерти Пушкина и даже свой какой-то Аля
report Alya about it But I didn't
доклад делала на это Но я никому не
tell anyone this just for myself  things I
говорила это просто для себя дела
see Wikipedia is all there is no
Понятно Википедия это всё там нет прямо
100% reliable information But
стопроцентно достоверной информации Но
from everything I found  from all the
из всего что я нашла из всех каких-то
records of all this I came to the conclusion
записей вот этого всего я сделала Вывод
that his murder was
что его короче убийство было
ordered, yes, the fact that the duel was a fake, yes, it was
заказное да то что дуэль - это фейк это
a fake, yes, Alexander or whoever
фейк Да Александром или кто там тогда
ruled then, Alexander III, yes, so I came to the
правил Александр III Да вот и я короче
conclusion that it was Alexander III who
сделала Вывод что это Александр III
ordered the murder of Pushkin  because he
заказал убийство Пушкина потому что он
knew too much since he had
слишком много знал так как у него был
access to the archive Pushkin Well it was investigated a long time ago
доступ к архиву Пушкин ж Ну уже давно
under the Soviet Union Yes
расследован был При Советском Союзе Да
Pushkin was killed And the press said that it
Пушкина убили А в прессе сказали что это
was a fate And so on and the one who was
было доль И так дальше и тот кто был
Pushkin's second Yes it was Honore de
секундантом Пушкина Да это Оноре де
Balzac  Three days later they found him hanged,
Бальзак его Через 3 дня нашли повешенным
another piece
о ещё одно
of evidence. There's a really murky
доказательство Да там вообще мутная
story with this Dantes. He's also a
история с этим дантесом ещё он тоже
complicated guy. And Dantes. Who was
такой непростой тип А у Дантеса Кто был
this second? You know, no, no,
этим секундантом знаешь нет нет
Cervantes. Yes, I know
Сервантес Да я вот знаю
that he's a tough guy, and this Cervantes
что тный чел и этот Сервантес после
moved to Spain after the duel.  no longer
дуэли переехал в Испанию и больше не
pressed Oh my gosh,
прижал
I read an interesting fact that
вот я вычитала интересный факт что
Dantes was the adopted son of some grandfather,
Дантес был приёмным сыном какого-то деда
but he was taken in, adopted when he
но его приютили усыновили когда ему уже
Dantes was already 18 some Grandfather
было 18 Дантес его какой-то Дед
just
просто себе
adopted him funny fact Not some Grandfather but a
усыновил забавный факт Не какой-то Дед а
rather famous Grandfather well probably
довольно известный Дед ну наверное
quite famous I don't remember anymore I
довольно известный Я уже не помню я в
wrote all this in the ninth grade well well
девятом классе это всё писала вот ну то
you definitely know this Grandfather
Вы точно этого деда знаете
Count Monte no no  I know Count of Monte Cristo
Граф Монте не не знаю Граф Монтекристо
he adopted Dantes Antes well then he
он усыновил Дантеса антес ну потом
attributes that he killed Pushkin yes
приписывает что он убил Пушкина да
yes Well that's how they usually say Pushkin died
да Ну вот как обычно говорят Пушкин умер
because he went to
потому что пошёл
find women
найто женщины
live
жи
Pushkin top 10 interesting facts about
Пушкин топ 10 интересных фактов о
writers well that's well definitely not a single one Have
писателях ну это ну однозначно ни одного
you seen when according to
Вы видели когда по
history
истори
he was Yesenin  Pushkin and Yesenin were messing around
он Есенин был Пушкин с есениным мутили
Wow, and after that Yesenin
Ого да И после этого Есенин же потом
committed suicide after
покончил жизнь самоубийством после
the murder of Pushkin. And he lived for about 14
убийства Пушкина А Он прожил что-то 14
months and 88 days,
месяцев 88 дней пон жизнь самоубийством
he couldn't live without Pushkin. The thing is
он не мог жить без Пушкина Дело в том
that Yesenin was very vulnerable, you know,
что Есенин Он был очень ранимый знаешь
like swans when  In swans, one of the pair
как лебеди когда у лебедей один из пары
dies, the other rises high into the sky
умирает второй поднимается высоко в небо
and falls and crashes on the rocks. That's it
и падает разбивается об скалы Вот и
Yesenin also he did not
Есенин также он не
survive the loss of Pushkin
пережил утрату Пушкина
and But by the way I know
и А вот я кстати знаю произведение у
Pushkin's work by heart the
Пушкина наизусть
prophet
пророк
super what is also an interesting fact
супер какой тоже интересный факт
and what do you think Why did Pushkin
а как ты Как ты считаешь Почему Пушкин
have a relationship with Yesenin
имел отношение с есениным
oh honestly I don't know you have to ask him well you
ой честно я не знаю его спрашивать надо
can't ask him anymore as if  Well, Yesenin is
ну его уже не спросишь как бы ну Есенин
such a handsome, cute boy, who wouldn't
такой красивый смазливый мальчик кому не
like him? Well, yes, Pushkin is hot, this
понравится Ну да Пушкин горячий этот
African. Yes, he is an African.
африканский Да африканец
They have a good one.
Хороший у них
Du, but he wanted to be
Ду а он хотел
jealous so that Lermontov would be jealous.
приревновал чтобы его Лермонтов ревновал
Probably not Lermontov. This is a slightly different
наверно не лермон это немножко другая
era. I mean, they crossed paths with
Эпоха В смысле они же пересекались с
Lermontov. No, Pushkin died in Lermontov's
Лермонтовым нет Пушкину лермантова на
arms. I'm
руках
kidding.
прикалываюсь
no he is on
нет него на
Rukh then the
Рух потом хотворение
poet's desire No he did that The poet died but he did
поэт Нет он то сделал Погиб поэт но он
not die in
не умирал на руках у
Lermontov's arms That's Lermontov
Лермонтова Вот это Лермонтов да
yes now I'll even just look at the era
м сейчас я даже просто эпоху посмотрю
when Pushkin Pushkin is the 10th century
когда Пушкин Пушкин - это X век
Lermontov
Лермонтов
[music]
[музыка]
it turns out also the 19th century they are in one
получается тоже XIX века они в одном в
they lived in the same era  poets of the same century and
одной эпохе жили они поэты одного века а
[music]
[музыка]
not Pushkin died in thirty-seventh but
не Пушкин умер в тридцать седьмом а
Lermontov Tamm in forty-first So
лермон тамм аж В сорок первом Так что
they do not intersect Well yes but I say that
они не пересека Ну да но я говорю что
they are of the same era they lived together in the 19th
они одной эпохи они жили вместе в XIX
century
веке
but Pushkin he died in
но Пушкин он умирал на руках у
Lermontov's arms about this  even Lermontov
лермантова про это даже Лермонтов
said they
говорил они
crossed paths how is it
пересекались какже
Yesenin that means he not only
Есенин то он значит не только с есениным
stirred up guns with Yesenin damn beetle if only he was with
мутил пушки блин жук бы он ещё с
Lermontov Yes that's what I'm saying so that
Лермонтов Да вот я говорю чтобы
Lermontov would be jealous probably understood
Лермонтов ревновал наверное понял
Okay I'll probably go already because it's already
ладно буду наверное уже идти а то уже
late Well yes I probably need to too How are
поздно Ну да Мне тоже наверное надо Как
you  do you think by the way, you know who
ты считаешь кстати вот ты знаешь кто
Ilya Kiva was a politician in Ukraine,
такой Илья кива был политик в Украине
no, it's very interesting, too, such a
не вот очень интересно тоже такой
paradox is called the Ilya Kiva Paradox,
Парадокс называется Парадокс иль кивы
that when Ilya Kiva moved from Ukraine
что когда Илья кива Переехал из Украины
to Russia, the average level of intelligence
в Россию то средний уровень интеллекта
increased in both countries How does this
вырос в обеих странах Как так
happen? Wow, what a joke, a proven
получается Нифига себе прикол доказанный
fact, yes  and it's called the Kiva effect
факт да и называется эффект кивы
Kova from Ukraine pere
Кова из Укра пере
in the level of intelligence has increased in both
в уровень интеллекта вырос в обоих
countries funny
странах забавный
fact don't know
факт не знаешь
why Yes
почему Да
no got it Well I  I don't know hoo on this
нет понял Ну я не знаю хоо на этой ноте
positive note we end the conversation yes
позитивной мы заканчиваем разговор да
Paradox or kiva confirmed
Парадокс или кивы подтвердился
Let it be
Пусть будет
so If you ever doubt that
так Если вы когда-то сомневаетесь что
such people
такие люди
exist they
существуют они
exist 1% of 100 100% of 100
существуют 1% от 100 100% от 100
20% oh-oh-oh
20% ой-ой-ой
poor
бедный
guns But Sanya Prokhorov
пушки Но Саня Прохоров
today I wrote Red and
сегодня написал Красное и
Black something else and the master Margarita
чёрное что-то там ещё а мастер Маргариту
and the Headless Horseman because Sanya
и Всадник без головы потому что Саня
Prokhorova in our other series everywhere VS the
Прохорова у нас в других сериях всюду ВС
headless gardener drone
садник без головы дроном
head like Yes 777 this is unique
башку лайк Да 777 это уникальное
will never be divided into this only
никогда не будет делиться на это только
777 here is the number 7  there is no such feature The
777 вот у числа 7 такой особенности нет
number 11 has such a feature No, it's
У числа 11 такой особенности Нет это
only 777 and zero is not a number By the way, who
только 777 а ноль не цифра Кстати кто
was laughing
там смеялся
with the digital root digital root - This is
с цифровой корень цифровой корень - Это
not a joke in mathematics there is a concept of a froy
не прикол в математике есть понятие фрой
root that I must have this is a
корень то что я обя это есть
neutral element a neutral element
нейтральный элемент нейтральный элемент
also there is such a concept that  this means
тоже есть такое понятие что это означает
this is an element that does not change the
это элемент который не меняет Да
value of the operation. For example, for the
значение операции Вот например для
operation  plus zero is a neutral
операции плюс нолик - это нейтральный
element no matter how much you add zero the number will
элемент сколько не добавляй ноль число
not change for the operation multiply
не изменится для операции умножить
one neutral element no matter how much you
единица нейтральный элемент сколько не
multiply by one the number will not change
умножая на единицу число не изменится
that some things you were laughing at in the chat
что некоторые вещи вы там в чате
some kind of joke it does not bring 100 100
бли какой-то Прикол это не прино 100 100
rocket like subscribe comment make
ракета лайк подписка коммент сделайте
I get 100% likes from 100% from 100
мне 100% лайков от 100% от 100
views subscribe to my Telegram
просмотров подпишись на мий Telegram
right now os win
прям зараз ось вин
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through scarg Orcs in your ban and very
нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show people sometimes I don't
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams that's
показуе информация про стримы тому для
why  we Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
is written right now and while there in telegram
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm video there is also interesting and useful
окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we are sorry with you
информация и ми повинни з вами тримати
timely operational link
постийний оперативный звязок
independent in that will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава Украине пись
with
с